http://www.wildlifevictoria.org.au/privacy-policy

Volunteer
HomeGet InvolvedVolunteerFundraise For UsTraining Days & RegistrationKnit Pouches for Orphaned JoeysDonateDonate to Wildlife VictoriaHow You Can HelpFundraise For UsSet Up A Monthly DonationEventsTraining DaysEvents CalendarWildlife InformationWildlife Fact Sheets How To Help VideosReport a Wildlife EmergencyStatisticsBuy a Possum BoxSchool Education ProgramHistorical DataFAQ'sGrantsCarer Grants InformationInfrastructure Grants InformationRescuer GrantsAbout UsAbout UsThe TeamBoard of ManagementEmergency Response ServiceEmploymentSupportersOur PublicationsContact Us
Facebook
Twitter
Instagram
YouTube
Privacy Policy
Wildlife Victoria is committed to protecting your privacy. We invite you to read this privacy policy, which explains our privacy practices and how we treat your personal information. It describes the types of personal information collected and created in connection with your interaction with Wildlife Victoria, how and why we use such information and who we share it with. We will only use the personal information that we collect about you in accordance with the Australian Privacy Principles (APPs).
The following definitions apply in this Privacy Policy:
“Personal information” is any information or an opinion about an identified individual or an individual that is reasonable identifiable:
whether the information or opinion is true or not; and
whether the information or opinion is recorded in a material form or not.
“Sensitive information” is information about an individual’s health, racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, membership of a political, professional, trade association or union, religious or philosophical beliefs, sexual orientation or practice, criminal record, and certain biometric information.
Personal Information We Collect
The type of personal information we will collect about you may include:
Your name
Address
Telephone number
Email address
Credit/debit card details
Personal website information, including cookies and other information about your computer, device and browser.
Volunteers
When applying to volunteer with Wildlife Victoria, the personal information we collect may include the information already listed above as well as your date of birth, relevant training and volunteer experience.  We may also collect sensitive information (such as information on a health condition). We also require a Police Check to be completed and education volunteers attending schools will require a Working with Children Check.
Job applicants and contractors
When applying for a position as an employee or a contractor with us, we also collect personal information necessary for us to perform functions related to recruitment, hiring and contract management. The personal information we collect may include that information already listed above as well as education history, qualifications, previous employers, membership of professional organisations and referee contact details.
Depending on your advancement in the recruitment process we may also collect your tax file number, bank account details, and other personal information (which might include sensitive information) from you in job interviews or telephone conversations and from your referees.
How we collect your personal information?
We will collect personal information directly from you when you contact Wildlife Victoria via phone, email, in person or online via our website. For volunteers we collect personal information from a third party in the form of the results of a Police Check and Working with Children Check.
Why we collect, hold, use and disclose your personal information
Your personal information is collected for the purpose of processing  donations, membership or training fees, issuing tax receipts, arranging to send assistance to an injured animal,  conducting research or surveys, issuing you with important updates about wildlife; keeping you up to date with our latest news and purposes related to those described above which would reasonably be expected by you.
If you are applying for a job your personal information is used to process your application. If you are applying to be a volunteer, we will use your personal information to process your application, and if you are successful, to manage your volunteer activities.
Your personal information may be shared with trusted service providers (for example the bank, PayPal, our secure database provider) or an employee or volunteer who we assign to attend the animal you reported to our Wildlife Emergency Response Service. You may choose not to provide this information but it may limit our ability to provide a receipt and/or rescue service. We may disclose your personal information to third parties where required by law and to anyone else to whom you authorise us to disclose it.
We do not ever sell or swap your information with other charities or data houses.  We do not disclose your personal information to overseas recipients. We may also store personal information in the ‘cloud’ which may mean that it resides on servers which are situated outside Australia.
Wildlife Victoria is a non-profit organisation that relies on donations to provide our Wildlife Emergency Service. If you contact our Wildlife Emergency Service and share your phone number, address or email address you may be contacted by Wildlife Victoria (or an agent acting on our behalf) at a later date for fundraising purposes. If you do not wish to receive any further contact you can opt out at the time of your call, or at any time afterwards.
Accuracy of your Personal Information
It is an important to us that your Personal Information is up to date and accurate. We will take reasonable steps to make sure that your Personal Information is accurate, complete and up-to-date. You can access and check the information that we hold about you by contacting:
Email: This email address is being protected from spambots. You need JavaScript enabled to view it.Phone: 03 9445 0310Postal Address: PO Box 100, Abbotsford, Victoria, 3067
If you find any inaccuracies and we agree with your request we will normally delete or correct it promptly. We may deny your request to access or correct your personal information where we are permitted to by law. We will provide reasons if we deny your request and information about the complaint mechanisms available.
Security of Personal Information
We may hold your personal information in either electronic or hard copy form.  We will take reasonable steps to ensure the personal information which we hold will be held securely in accordance with our Privacy Policy and in accordance with the APPs.
Cookies
We may use technology to track the patterns of behaviour of visitors to our site, including the number of visitors and the pages browsed. This can include using a "cookie" which would be stored on your browser. You can usually modify your browser to prevent this happening. The information collected in this way can be used to identify you unless you modify your browser settings.
Policy Updates
This Policy may change from time to time. The current version is available on our website.
Queries and Complaints
If you have any questions or comments about your privacy, including a copy of our Privacy Policy you should contact us.
If you have a complaint about how we handle your personal information, please contact:
Email: This email address is being protected from spambots. You need JavaScript enabled to view it.Phone: 03 9445 0310Postal Address: PO Box 100, Abbotsford, Victoria, 3067
If your complaint is not resolved to your satisfaction or we have not responded to you within 30 days you have the right to contact the Australian Information Commissioner.
Office of the Australian Information Commissioner
GPO Box 5218Phone: 1300 363 992Email: This email address is being protected from spambots. You need JavaScript enabled to view it.
Approved by Board of Management 24th June 2019
Our activity
in your area.
Explore the map to see which animals were in need of our help in your local area last month. The points on this map all relate to a single animal, or family of animals, reported to Wildlife Victoria last month. (Yes, this is just one month!)
" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen>
HomeGet InvolvedVolunteerFundraise For UsTraining Days & RegistrationKnit Pouches for Orphaned JoeysDonateDonate to Wildlife VictoriaHow You Can HelpFundraise For UsSet Up A Monthly DonationEventsTraining DaysEvents CalendarWildlife InformationWildlife Fact Sheets How To Help VideosReport a Wildlife EmergencyStatisticsBuy a Possum BoxSchool Education ProgramHistorical DataFAQ'sGrantsCarer Grants InformationInfrastructure Grants InformationRescuer GrantsAbout UsAbout UsThe TeamBoard of ManagementEmergency Response ServiceEmploymentSupportersOur PublicationsContact Us
Facebook
Twitter
Instagram
YouTube
WILDNET Login
Privacy PolicyDisclaimerSitemap© Copyright Wildlife Victoria
site designed by Mity Digital
Donate Now!
HomeGet InvolvedVolunteerFundraise For UsTraining Days & RegistrationKnit Pouches for Orphaned JoeysDonateDonate to Wildlife VictoriaHow You Can HelpFundraise For UsSet Up A Monthly DonationEventsTraining DaysEvents CalendarWildlife InformationWildlife Fact Sheets How To Help VideosReport a Wildlife EmergencyStatisticsBuy a Possum BoxSchool Education ProgramHistorical DataFAQ'sGrantsCarer Grants InformationInfrastructure Grants InformationRescuer GrantsAbout UsAbout UsThe TeamBoard of ManagementEmergency Response ServiceEmploymentSupportersOur PublicationsContact Us
Facebook
Twitter
Instagram
YouTube
